export const questions = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "What is React or ReactJS?",
    options: [
      "Component-based Javascript library",
      "Javascript framework",
      "Javascript file",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Component-based Javascript library",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "Which of the following comes under the advantages of React?",
    options: [
      "Integration with other frameworks (like BackboneJS, Angular, etc.) becomes easier because it is only a view library",
      "Increases the performance of an application using Virtual DOM",
      "Can render both on server and client side",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "All of the above",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question:
      "The number of elements that can be returned by a valid React component is ______.",
    options: ["5", "1", "3", "2"],
    answer: "1",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question:
      "What is the declarative approach for rendering a dynamic list of components depending on array values?",
    options: [
      "Using <Each/> component",
      "Using reduce array method",
      "Using Array.map() method",
      "Using for or while loop",
    ],
    answer: "Using Array.map() method",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "What is meant by the state in React?",
    options: [
      "Internal storage of component",
      "External storage of component",
      "Permanent storage",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Internal storage of component",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: "Which command can be used for the creation of React app?",
    options: [
      "npx install create-react-app my-app",
      "install -g create-react-app",
      "npm install create-react-app my-app",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "npx install create-react-app my-app",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "What is used for passing the data to a component from outside?",
    options: ["Render with arguments", "setState", "PropTypes", "props"],
    answer: "props",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: "______ will help to keep the data unidirectional in React.",
    options: ["Dom", "Props", "JSX", "Flux"],
    answer: "Flux",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question:
      "Which of the following statements related to the “webpack” command is true?",
    options: [
      "It runs React local development server",
      "It is used to transpile all the JavaScript into a single file",
      "It is a module bundler",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "It is a module bundler",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "What are the ReactJS limitations?",
    options: [
      "React will use inline templating and JSX which might seem awkward to a few developers",
      "ReactJS is only for the view layer of the application, which means we will make use of other technologies as well for getting complete tooling set for the application development",
      "The React library is too large",
      "All of these",
    ],
    answer: "All of these",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: "What is the usage of setState?",
    options: [
      "Replacing the state fully instead of the default merge action",
      "Accessing the earlier state before the setState operation",
      "Invoking the code after the setState operation is performed",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Invoking the code after the setState operation is performed",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: "The Keys given to a list of elements in React should be ______.",
    options: [
      "Not necessarily unique",
      "Unique among the siblings only",
      "Unique in the DOM (Document Object Model)",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Unique among the siblings only",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question:
      "What function will permit for rendering the React content in an HTML page?",
    options: [
      "React.render()",
      "ReactDOM.start()",
      "React.mount()",
      "ReactDOM.render()",
    ],
    answer: "ReactDOM.render()",
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: "React is mainly used for developing ______.",
    options: ["Connectivity", "Database", "User interface", "Design platform"],
    answer: "User interface",
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: " ______ is a necessary API for every React.js component.",
    options: [
      "renderComponent",
      "render",
      "SetinitialComponent",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "renderComponent",
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question:
      "Which of the following is used in React.js to increase performance?",
    options: [
      "Virtual DOM",
      "Original DOM",
      "Both A and B",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Virtual DOM",
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question: "What is ReactJS?",
    options: [
      "Server-side framework",
      "user interface framework",
      "both a and b",
      "none of the above",
    ],
    answer: "user interface framework",
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: "Who created React.js?",
    options: ["Jordan Mike", "Jordan Walke", "Tim Lee", "Jordan Lee"],
    answer: "Jordan Walke",
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question: "In which language is React.js written?",
    options: ["Python", "JavaScript", "Java", "PHP"],
    answer: "JavaScript",
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question: "What is Babel?",
    options: [
      "JavaScript compiler",
      "JavaScript interpreter",
      "JavaScript transpiler",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "JavaScript transpiler",
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question: "In MVC, what does React.js act as?",
    options: ["Model", "Controller", "View", "Middleware"],
    answer: "View",
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    question: "Identify the smallest building block of React.JS.",
    options: ["Props", "Elements", "Components", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Components",
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    question:
      "Which of the following function is used to change the state of react component?",
    options: [
      "this.setState()",
      "this.state()",
      "this.setChangeState()",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "this.setState()",
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    question: "Which of the following are two ways to handle data in react?",
    options: [
      "services and components",
      "State and props",
      "state and services",
      "state and component",
    ],
    answer: "this.setState()",
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    question: "ES6 stands for _________",
    options: ["ECMA 6", "ECMAJavaScript 6", "ECMAScript 6", "EJavaScript 6"],
    answer: "ECMAScript 6",
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    question: "Choose the method with refers to the parent class in ReactJS?",
    options: ["this()", "super()", "iniherits()", "self()"],
    answer: "super()",
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    question: "JSX stands for __________",
    options: ["Javascript XML", "JSON XML", "JSON", "Javascript and AngularJS"],
    answer: "Javascript XML",
  },
];
